Contact

Carabobo, Venezuela des.luistena@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/luistena (LinkedIn) luistena.is-a.dev (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Python

Django

FastAPI

Certifications

SQL (Basic)

Relational Database

Rest API (Intermediate)

Back End Development and APIs

Python Basics

Luis Tena

Back-End Engineer | CEO @ Asapiens

Venezuela

Summary

With +10 years of experience, I started my journey with the entrepreneurship of a job posting website called HireInVenezuela, using Bootstrap, Django, and PostgreSQL from 2014 for approximately 2 years.

After finishing college, I developed Softour in 2018 (a tourism website built with Bootstrap, Express.js (Node.js), and MongoDB) for another 2 years.

Later, I worked as a Front-End developer using React (JavaScript) and as a DevOps engineer for a delivery app called Don Demand. During my 3 years there, I extensively used Linux and open source tools for deployments and enhanced my teamwork skills.

Afterward, I served as a Back-End JavaScript/TypeScript developer for a remote multicultural team spanning Portugal, India, Egypt, the Netherlands, the UK, Slovenia, and other countries. This experience allowed me to learn how to adapt to different schedules and English accents.

Now, I'm building a startup called Asapiens, with the product Vitrinapp for the webcomics industry.

Portfolio (WIP): https://luistena.is-a.dev

GitHub: https://github.com/devluist

Experience

Accelerator App Back End Developer January 2023 - September 2023 (9 months) Lisbon, Portugal

- Created an internal Admin Panel to manage certain features of the AcceleratorApp product.
- App and queues development in Nest.js to allow internal metrics about users and their interactions. I used a MongoDB to PostgreSQL ETL connected to Google Looker
- Miscellaneous deployments using GitHub CI and debugging of app errors using DataDog

EmQu Technologies

Back-end Developer

September 2022 - December 2022 (4 months)

México, Mexico

- Back-End development of API using FastAPI / Python with TDD
- Consul + Nomad for DevOps setup

SIM Venezuela

Full-stack Developer

June 2018 - August 2021 (3 years 3 months)

Cumaná, Sucre, Venezuela

- DevOps:
- * Site Reliability Engineering
- * Sentry, Prometheus, and Grafana SQL/PromQL queries for reports, health checks, and monitoring
- * Automation Scripting development of Bash/Python scripts
- * Servers setup: Nginx, domains, non-sudo users, custom ports, set ssh keys, firewall setup, etc
- React.js
- * Co-developer on some of the React projects for clients
- * and also for internal products at the company like Don Demand and other apps

Softour

Entrepreneur

September 2017 - March 2018 (7 months)

Venezuela

Web app for data collection to increase tourism. This was a college project, made with Node.js / Express.js and MongoDB.

I was in charge of the Backend, Architecture, and Admin Dashboard.

I implemented Factory and Strategy Design patterns on the API.

This demo is based in Sucre state, Venezuela.

Check the code at https://github.com/devluist/softour

Hire in Venezuela

Entrepreneur

December 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 4 months)

Cumana, Sucre, Venezuela

This was a Venezuelan freelancing marketplace web app that I developed myself.

You can see a demo https://youtu.be/EGY_NsZGuSc

- Backend made with Python2.5 / Django 1.8
- Frontend made with CSS3 + Boostrap3 and HTML5
- Deployments through Openshift services

Education

Universidad de Oriente (VE)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2018)